# **Syed Hasnain Bukhari**

# Bangkok



#### About

Full Stack Developer with 5+ years of rich professional experience of building and delivering highly scalable, enterprise grade software products. I hold a Bachelor's degree in Computer Sciences from the Punjab University College of Information Technology, Lahore, Pakistan

**Phone:** (+66) 630789575. (+92) 3017924305 **Email:** syedhasnainbukhari01@hotmail.com

#### **Work Experience**

#### Agoda

#### Full Stack Software Engineer

2021 - Present

Leading several teams, working on solutions based upon distributed computing to make the e-commerce scene under the global travel space alive

- Working with teams to migrate long-running legacy systems to a newer and a better stack
- Keeping track of the learning abilities of my team so that they can progress in their respective careers and interests
- Having 1:1s to shape up the team culture and align them with essential matters at the organization
- Build a mindset and culture of quality first; Owning our stuff and converting them to quality artefacts and systems
- Help the organization envision what moving away from legacy could mean and preach the benefits within the team(s)
- Help the team understand Agility at work and take them through ceremonies; This helps the team give their best following sprints
- Making an effort around organizational values, so it lives within the team and work we do.

# Strategic System International

#### Senior Software Engineer

2019 - 2021

Provided leadership across the engineering organization for the aspects of hiring, processes, architecture, grooming individuals and solving complex problems

- Introduced a hiring process and its custodianship (aka The Hiring Squad!)
- Enabled the eco-system of documentation keeping and taking tools along with helping the team to use them day-in-day-out
- Conducted 1:1s with team members to keep their inspirations and motivations up
- Helped to bootstrap various products for a quick test with the upcoming consumer markets for the organization
- Been a part of the team and the solution for complex problems like NotificationCenter, Auth provider selection and payment gateway solution
- Created and vocalized a process of hiring interns and turning them into fellow beings

- Led and represented the engineering department of the organization
- Proactively participated in converting an old-school organization to an organization with agility
- Helped and created career progression for various individuals in the organization
- Proactively involved me with HR to discuss and demystify challenging problems
- Introduced and have been the most potent catalyst in changing our product platform to be the cross-platform product
- Enabled ways to bring in new dimensions to the product evolution, which were held back because of the absence of engineering leadership
- Focus on quality deliverables -- Provided guidance to bring in an appropriate SDLC
- I got involved and got my hands dirty with architecture decisions at various organizational levels

#### **CureMD**

#### **Software Engineer**

2017 - 2019

SEEK is a diverse group of companies that have a unified purpose to help people live more fulfilling and productive working lives and help organisations succeed.

- Contributed to SEEKs overall product & technology strategy and aligned systems with that strategy
- Ensured that systems were fit for purpose, well-architected and followed current SEEK development practices
- Maintained platform health by ensuring that our systems are secure, reliable, resilient and cost-effective
- Drove customer focus to ensure that we deliver excellent outcomes for our customers
- Commenced and maintained a high performing team culture that values collaboration, learning and continual improvement
- Acted as an enabler; Grew my team's technical skills and leadership capabilities through coaching and mentoring. This involves having 1:1s with my teammates
- Lead by example, Which required me to get my hands dirty when needed
- Unblocked the team with whatever it took, having complete ownership of maintaining healthy teams
- Celebrated successes and learnt from the failures; propagated the culture through the teams and exemplified it for the rest of the organization
- Paired with the Principal Engineer of the team to understand the climate and the team's problems
- Participated in and retro-ed the core hiring process through a centralized hiring squad
- Helped the org to move fast to the ecosystem of global products; Away from the local products which we have been dealing with for the past 25+ years

# **Logix Infinity**

#### **Software Engineer**

2016 - 2017

SEEK is a diverse group of companies that have a unified purpose to help people live more fulfilling and productive working lives and help organisations succeed.

- Been the catalyst for transforming the organization
- Performed the duties as the JavaScript coach for the organization
- Advocated for and implemented software best practices
- Have been the communicator for various teams to maintain their health; sometimes preached the organization's values
- Participated as a core in hiring new and experienced talents
- Propagated automation as a culture rather than an option
- Moved legacy code and data to cloud via lift & shift, greenfield and brownfield methodologies
- Performed the duties of deciding and validating sensible defaults for the organization
- Pushed cloud-first approach in the org, living in an environment of Infra ops
- With the help of fellow architects, I invested time in a flourishing framework of single identity throughout SEEK systems; We did this through educating, enabling, and supporting the needful tools for the teams

• Created several SDKs for a single identity solution within Seek with complete automation and tests. Later helped teams adopt them into various systems

#### **Education**

#### **FAST - NUCES**

#### **Computer Science, Bachelor**

2006 - 2010

### **Skills**

#### • Web Development

- HTML
- Javascript

#### • Software Architecture

- Design-patterns
- Distributed systems
- Scalability
- Maintainability

#### • Software Development

- Sustainability
- Portability
- Scalability
- Reasonability

#### Problem Solving

- CompetitiveProgramming
- Abstract

#### • Draft documentation

- docsify
- Github
- MARP
- Joplin
- MermaidJS
- FormsIO

#### • Communication

- face-2-face
- emails
- presentations
- conference
- o buy-in talks

- o negotiations
- layman conversions
- 1:1s

## References

Amir is surely missed by his team/peers and I think any company would find great benefit with the addition of Amir to their leadership and technical team. Wish you all the best Amir and hope our paths cross again. - **Heinrich Rust** 

As a colleague Amir is friendly, personable, has an easy manner and great sense of humour. A clear communicator with a voice for radio, Amir is wise head on young shoulders. - **Paul Fitzgerald**